PERSONAL DETAILS

Anil SASMAL

Puri, India

Pin Code: 752104 M: +91 9606588547

E: SASMALDBS@gmail.com

DOB: 15/04/1991 Passport: Yes Nationality: Indian Marital Status: Single Langs: English, Hindi

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Database Migration to Cloud, Oracle to pgsql migration using ORA2PG, ASCT tool, DMS

- Oracle Installation
- RMAN, Backup & Recovery
- Patching & Upgradation
- Oracle RAC
- Oracle Data Guard
- Performance Tuning
- Capacity Planning
- Monitoring Setup
- Automation & Scripting
- PGSOL Administration
- MSSQL Administration
- Learning New Technology

ACHIVEMENTS

Received the title of "Star of business award" in the year 2017.

Winner of the "FY20 O4 Accenture Celebrate Excellence Awards" in the vear 2020.

CERTIFICATION

AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate

PERSONAL SKILLS

Ability to teach & Mentor

Prioritization & Initiative

Investigative & Motivated

Adaptability & flexible

ORACLE & EXADATA DBA

MS SQL SERVER & PostgreSQL DBA

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Experience as Database Administration, and knowledge in Systems Analysis and Design, Development and Documentation at various levels. An accomplished Database administrator (DBA) with expertise in technical skills and knowledge fruitful for the growth of the firm.

WORK EXPERIENCE

HCL Technologies LTD Technical Specialist

Noida, India 06/2022 - Till Date

Responsibilities:

- ❖ Experienced in working on Exadata machines X6/X7/X8M/X9M.
- Maintaining and Troubleshooting Exadata Cell/Storage and DB/Compute node performance issues.
- Proving end to end support for the Exadata hardware and software.
- Experience in administering ASM,RAC,DG both in Exadata and Non-Exadata.
- Run exachk, sosreport, sundiag & ilom snpashots to diagnosis exadata health check
- Tracing, troubleshooting with database performance and tuning issues.
- Performing database migration from Oracle to PostgreSQL using ORA2PG tool.
- * Hands on experience on administering and managing Postgres and SQL Server databases.

ACCENTURE SOLUTION PVT LTD

Bangalore, India 05/2016 - 06/2022

Cloud Operations Senior Analyst

Responsibilities:

Supporting more than 2000 instances.

- Working experience in EXADATA platform
- Interacting, assisting the DC teams and co-ordinate with Oracle engineers to fix hardware issue & faulty device replacement & Exadata patching.
- Worked on Oracle database migration in cross platform environment (windows to Linux) using Oracle Dataguard in cloud and on premises.
- Experience in administering ASM both in Exadata and Non-Exadata.
- Experience in administering Oracle RAC.
- * Performing database creation & decommissions.
- * Tracing, troubleshooting with database performance and tuning issues.
- * Data guard configuration & switchover
- * Patching standalone databases, Grid databases.
- * Performing database Upgrade manually & using DBUA.
- * Oracle database backup, restoration, cloning using RMAN.
- * Monitoring & performing database activities through OEM.
- ** Handling Incidents, Changes, Problems ticket.
- * Installing, Configuring & Maintaining MSSQL Server Instance.
- ** MSSQL Server Backup, Restore & Maintenance plan.
- * Experience in MSSQL Server Patching & Upgrade.
- **Co-ordinating with team members & train new members.**

FUTURE FOCUS INFOTECH PVT LTD

System Engineer

Kolkata, India 12/2015 - 05/2016

Responsibilities:

- Supporting more than 500 instances.
- Handling Incidents, Changes, Problems
- * Performing database creation & decommissions.
- Maintenance of production database and development database which includes tablespace space
- Tracing, troubleshooting with database performance and tuning issues.
- Patching standalone databases

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Graduation: B.Tech(IT) Orissa Engineering College, Odisha 2008 - 2012 12th Intermediate: Science: P.N. College, Odisha **2006 - 2008** 10th Class: Maths: ATBN High School, Odisha 2005 - 2006